

**Burak Kanmaz** 

Technology Consultant



+90 (538) 778 90 86



burak@kanmaz.net



12 Apr, 1987

Burak, who is married and has two children, has worked professionally on Microsoft technologies for over 14 years. At the same time, he works by following trend technologies regularly and being open to innovations. With his innovative personality, he attaches great importance to quality, performance, and efficiency in all his work. He also applies this working principle in team and project management.

## **Work Experiences**

## **Technology Consultant**

Freelance January, 2023 - ....

He offers software and Jira consultancy services to both local and international companies. During his work, he has developed the Jira Plugin, Teams App, and Slack App products. He also continues upgrading his skills through certification studies on Jira and Azure while providing consultancy services.



## **Head of Technology**

Inooster April, 2022 - January, 2023

He was the Head of Technology at Turkey's most significant company that provided gamification solutions. After starting the business, he helped the company expand its gamification experience to various platforms by developing products in Jira. He oversaw and managed the company's five products and more than 20 customer portfolios, products, and technical processes. He also worked with two software teams that were under his supervision.



# Team Lead

Antasya May, 2021 - April, 2022

As the Team Lead of a seven-person software team, he managed the team's work and communicated with clients. He successfully managed 15 projects for five corporate companies, including three holdings, one bank, and one production facility.

Apart from managing the team, he also took charge of all technical work within the company. He actively managed the company's physical and digital technical assets, coordinated with other teams, and planned for the company's future.

He played a vital role in technical communication with clients and managing these processes during his tenure. He conducted over 75 interviews and helped expand the internal team. His expertise in Jira allowed the company to offer Jira Consulting services to its clients.



# **Solutions Architect**

Ericsson May, 2017 - Apr, 2021

He began working as a senior software developer on a team of 20 people for Turkcell, Turkey's largest GSM operator. The team was responsible for the call center flow management project.

In October 2017, he was responsible for handling one of the critical modules within the project. During the year he worked in this position, he acted as the contact person with the customer and served as a lead developer.

In October 2018, he was appointed as the Solutions Architect at the head of a team of 15 people, which was formed to maintain and develop Turkcell Global Bilgi's corporate applications. Throughout the process, he was responsible for establishing the team and managing relations with the customer. He provided

# Areas of Interest and Expertise

### **Backend Technologies**

.NET Framework, .NET Core, Node JS, ASP.NET MVC, C#, Java

# **Frontend Technologies**

React JS, Angular, Bootstrap, Typescript

## **Mobile Technologies**

Flutter, React Native

## **Data Store/Process Technologies**

EF, MSSQL, PL/SQL, PostreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ, Solr, Elastic Search (ELK)

#### **DevOps Technologies**

Windows Server, IIS, Linux, Docker, Azure, AWS, Cloudflare, Firewall

#### **Project Management Technologies**

Jira, Confluence, Azure DevOps, Git, TFS, Bitbucket

#### **Administrative Technologies**

Microsoft 365, Exchange, Teams, Azure, MPN, Cloudflare

Information Security and Pentest, CFP (Cosmic Function Point), Python

# **Technologies He Tries To Learn**

Artificial Intelligence, GPT-4, IoT, Blockchain

# Information Security

He has been working in information security as a hobby since 2012. He has provided security consultancy and pentest services to many companies during his studies. In addition to information security, he has provided consultation on social engineering, network security, penetration testing, and application security. He has worked with several companies in this regard.















development and technical support services for over 20 projects with his team.



#### **IT Manager**

## Istanbul Commodity Exchange 2015 - 2017

He was responsible for managing a team of five people in the information technology department and fulfilling all the software and hardware requirements of the company's 120 employees spread across five locations.

He restructured the network infrastructure, enhancing security and authorization by modifying internet access rules, file shares, and firewalls. Additionally, he optimized user authorizations to ensure maximum security and authorization. Moreover, he implemented a system to monitor, alert, and control all user actions within the network.



## **IT Manager Assistant**

# Ankara Sigorta 2014 - 2015

After discovering a security vulnerability on the Ankara Insurance website, he could access all source codes and databases. Upon notifying the company of the vulnerability, he was assigned as the Assistant Manager of the 12-person Information Technology team, responsible for overseeing the software.

His primary focus was addressing performance issues with the recently developed infrastructure using the .NET Framework.



## Senior Software Developer

# Doğan Gazetecilik 2012 - 2014

He was actively involved in the Live Score project to broadcast the results of various sports games live, focusing on football. The project was developed using ASP.NET MVC on MSSQL. To ensure faster score updates for visitors, he utilized Angular JS and Knockout JS. With the help of NetScaler, he created a system that could handle 65,000 visitors without any performance issues.



# Software Developer

Kariyer.net 2012 - 2012



# Software Developer

IRM Ajans 2009 - 2012

## **Awards and Achievements**

<u>o</u>	Ericsson awarded him a special appreciation award for his productive remote work with his team during the pandemic.	2020
<u>o</u>	He was also recognized as the "MMEA's 2019 Champions Award Winner" by Ericsson.	2019
<b>T</b>	Additionally, he won first place in the international Imagine Cup software competition held by Microsoft in Turkey.	2010
*	He was also selected twice as a Microsoft Student Partner.	2008, 2009
ð	He has authored a book on Windows 7.	2008

## **Educational Background**



## Postgraduate Computer Engineering

Istanbul University 2022 - ....

He has completed the course phase and is working on a thesis on "Security Analysis of Blockchain-based Applications."



## **Undergraduate** Sociology

Istanbul University 2020 - ....

He has pursued his interest in sociology and psychology by studying sociology through remote education.



# Undergraduate Computer Engineering

Istanbul University 2005 - 2010

During his undergraduate studies, the individual served as the computer club president and the department student representative and worked as a department laboratory assistant.